<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Awesome Arian&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://awesome.arianv.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Awesome Arian&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 14:44:58 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://awesome.arianv.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A day with the Authors</title>
      <link>http://awesome.arianv.com/a-day-with-the-authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 14:44:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://awesome.arianv.com/a-day-with-the-authors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Media is fascinating. Books, movies, art, games, music. To think how a belief, a view, an emotion, or a story, can be contained and conveyed in a particular medium is just mind-blowing - perhaps one of the most key things that distinguishes humans. The ability to connect emotionally through these is why I enjoy interacting with media so much - especially books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s quite interesting though, is the meta aspect of them - the thought that this isn’t just an experience that was seen or viewed through a window, so to speak. Instead, another person, another human being, somewhere, sometime, decided to sit down and concoct a story that he/she would later share with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last Thursday, I got to meet with two such people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ma’am invited Maita Songco Salvador and Marie Yvette Concepcion-Alcazar, the authors of the Children’s books “When Zero Left Number Land” and “Letting Sunny Go” respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t read any of the two books before, so I came to the class blind, but I really enjoyed both of them when they were read to us. “When Zero Left Number Land” had an incredibly cute story, and the book also ‘sounds’ good, having a nice rhyming pattern and a certain cadence to how it was written. Of course, the personification of numbers was a really quirky and fun sight to behold - you don’t always see a talking and judgeful ‘Nine’!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Letting Sunny Go” was a much heavier story, dealing with how a child gives up her favorite toy to donate it to calamity struck children. The book served as an interesting (and I’m pretty sure effective) way to convey the concept of donating, and further more, altruism to kids. It’s a feel good story, and it does a damn good job of being one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the stories, the authors then shared and talked about their creations, which made for a pretty insightful one and a half hour for our class. Putting the books to a face and seeing the authors in flesh was quite a different thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of their inception stories were very inspirational - talking about how they got started on Children’s Literature, writing lots of stuff, finding an idea they were willing to stick with, refining, publishing, and the creative process that went along with it… It was essentially a startup story, but in this case in the context of children’s books!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors’ story of how difficult it was for them to be constantly asked to revise their story by the publisher was something that really struck with me as a game developer, as I’ve also went through the same thing. A creation is something incredibly personal, and veering off from your initial visions is something that’s always quite a challenge to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the whole talk left me with a lot of inspiration - indeed the thought that maybe I can write a story too passed my mind! The whole talk showed me how the authors weren’t intimidating literature experts - rather, they were really just people who had an educational and moral story to tell the world, and published it through a dash of creativity, perseverance, and a whole lot of hard work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Child That Books Built</title>
      <link>http://awesome.arianv.com/the-child-that-books-built/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 16:13:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://awesome.arianv.com/the-child-that-books-built/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I still vividly remember the very first &amp;ldquo;children’s book&amp;rdquo; my mother got for me. &amp;ldquo;Jack and the Beanstalk&amp;rdquo;, it’s title was, the lush greenery of nature in the cover of which, was a stark contrast of the gray drab ‘urbanity’ of Metro Manila, where we stayed at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book reaffirmed within me this &lt;em&gt;strong desire for adventure, to not settle down and resign myself to fate, and to dream of the world that can be.&lt;/em&gt; A desire, I presume, all children had, that of innate curiosity for the world around us. What was new to me then however, was that it made me realize, that I should strive for them, even if it means confronting things I would not be comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title itself is a classic, the plot of which, I would assume is popular enough that it does not warrant another telling here. But this is also where I would try to seek light on a particular aspect of the story, one which might not be inherently evident to all readers. The thing was, even if the obvious antagonistic force in the story was the giant, it was never the giant that made me particularly uncomfortable. Instead, it happens much earlier in the story, in the scene where Jack decides to buy the magic beans. I couldn’t put it into words then, but this made me extremely uncomfortable, as essentially, Jack had to disobey his mother. For context I was 4 at the time, an age where I have not even thought of the idea of lying to my parents. Now, was the moral of the story to disobey your parents and accept random magic beans from strangers so that you can go on wild adventures? I would dare say no. But that single scene made such a tremendous impact on my life. A subconscious one that I could never really have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I would be hard pressed to believe a claim from a student that such a scene would make such an impact to his life, and indeed I would probably assume that such a student would only be writing it for the sake of submitting a paper or an essay, and I would not be surprised if this same essay is seen in the same way. But let me try to defend myself here. See, I believe that something as personal as a ‘formative’ event in one’s life, can only be properly understood once it is contextualized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a ‘trouble’ child my mother would always say. Not in the sense that I was a naughty, mischievous kid, but I was a ‘trouble’ child in the sense that I had lots of ‘trouble’ growing up. See, I was born with pediatric pneumonia, a condition which could have been fatal  and left me within the grounds of the hospital until I was in my early first year. I would grow up developmentally stunted, always behind my peers, and only beginning to make my first sounds when I was 2, a terribly late age to start doing so, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such relatively late development worried my mother, resigning her to the idea that I would grow up to be a ‘special child’ or a child with disability. Indeed when I came of age she was against the thought of letting me go to school, as she believed me unfit to study at the normal age. It was my antics then, that gave her the idea to try and letting me go to a normal school. Those ‘antics’ where things my mother noticed when I was growing up. How I would wake up in 8 in the morning to open the TV to watch “Epol’s Apple” and “Mathinik”. How I would be enamored by bedtime stories, the first of which was the aforementioned “Jack and the Beanstalk”. How I would wake up with my brother who was preparing for elementary school, so that I could go to school with him, with my family coming to stop me. Of course they would. I started doing that when I was only three years old. Apparently years of this pestered my mother enough that she decided to enroll me in school when the time came that I am of school age, where, to her surprise, I was able to learn in the same pace as normal kids would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where I try to close and bring it back full circle. It was agency and breaking of expectation, that I managed to come out with from “Jack and the Beanstalk”, something that I still take with me to this day. Had it not been for Jack’s desire and curiosity for the world, he would have probably foregone the magic beans for money. It is, in my view, the story not only of overcoming of great odds as Jack did with the giant, but of pursuing goals and dreams in the face of practical dilemma and inherent expectations, like Jack did when he was offered the magic beans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack&amp;rsquo;s choice to take the magic beans was the first ever story to confront me with taking risks. To this day, I face numerous choices and choose to take risks, not because of something I can explicitly explain, but due to that &lt;em&gt;strong desire for adventure, to not settle down and resign myself to fate, and to dream of the world that can be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I had thought of using “Jack and the Beanstalk” to start my essay, intending actually for “The Ugly Duckling” to be my ‘formative’ childhood story, as that had the most nascent impact in my life. But I found myself wallowing and overestimating one page of text, and I have now grossly overwritten my 1 page mark, so I shall end here and save that story for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>